# A.H. Shahrukh Khan

A passionate cloud native application developer and engineer (Dev-Ops) with the hands on experience of over 18 months of modern and advanced technologies.

I develop simpler but more powerful cloud native container based applications that can run on any cloud (AWS, Google Cloud, Azure, Red Hat, etc.).

My practices automate everything, thus enabling Continuous Integration and Continuous Deployment (CI/CD). As a Certified Kubernetes Application Developer Dev-Ops and team lead, I am capable to contribute to Cloud technologies using Kubernetes.

# **Professional Experience**

## Panacloud Consulting, London

**Role:** DevOps Engineer

September 2019 - PRESENT

Our specialty is in developing **custom technology solutions** utilizing emerging technologies to deliver tangible outcomes for our clients. We provide **onsite and offsite consulting services** for cloud native and automation technologies.

Best automation practices CI/CD with Jenkins, Infrastructure automation SAAS with Ansible, Terraform, and source control with Git and Github, containersation with Docker etc..

# Panacloud, London

Role: Cloud Native Application Developer

Client: Presidential Initiative for Artificial Intelligence & Computing (www.PIAIC.org)

March 2018 - PRESENT

Led a team of developers and cloud native engineers to build a highly scalable Kubernetes based web application and student portal, with data of over 50k users and projected to hit **100k daily active users** by the end of 2019 (www.piaic.org).

- Designed and developed a framework for automation on Containerized MERN (MongoDB, Express, React, and NodeJS) stack with Kubernetes.
- Supported the team to **containerize microservices** using Docker.
- Led team to build and implement microservices architecture to deploy the PIAIC web application using Kubernetes.
- Created technical design for project deliverables.
- Set up and built Docker Containers installation, building images, and deployments for hybrid infrastructure.
- Set up and built Kubernetes Clusters installation, configuration, optimization, scale-up and management.
- Code in YAML for Kubernetes architecture.
- Solved complex, cross-functional issues to help bring incidents to resolution.
- Develop custom scripts to increase efficiency in process and system, with the objective of reducing intervention on
  any repetitive tasks by using Git and Git hub to with CI/CD pipelines built in Jenkins Automation
   Deployed and managed HA web application on AWS K8 cluster using EC2 with proficiency of loadbalancing and autoscalling VPC. IAM of

Deployed and managed HA web application on AWS K8 cluster using EC2 with proficiency of loadbalancing and autoscalling, VPC, IAM etc., SCM with Ansible, developed playbooks utilising Atom IDE to code with Remote sync and Linter-js packeges to speed up the Automation.

#### Role:

### Chief Instructor for Cloud Native Specialist Program - March 2018 - PRESENT

Led the **train the trainer program** to prepare cloud native instructors for the Presidential Initiative for Artificial Intelligence and Computing. I have **trained 18 instructors**, all certified by the Cloud Native Computing Foundation's **Certified Kubernetes Application Developer** examinations.

- Conducted training sessions for PIAIC trainers focusing on: Linux, Docker, and Kubernetes.
- Prepared over **100 hours of video** content teaching cloud native technologies.
- Developed exams for PIAIC faculty and students in the cloud native specialist program.
- Created presentations on over 200 topics covering cloud native technologies.

10 Cavenham Two Mile Ash MK8 8JP, Milton Keynes, UK +44.791.232.4765

ahshahkhan@gmail.com Nationality British

#### **Skills**

- Cloud Native Computing
- DevOps
- Kubernetes Trainer
- Docker Trainer
- Project Manager
- Mobile & Web Application Development

GDPR

Linux

## **Recent Certifications**



## Primark, Corby, UK

## Role: Senior Manager

May 2017 - March 2018

Led and managed over 10 Million budget store with the management team of seven managers including an assistant store manager, senior department manager, four department managers, three supervisors, and 103 staff members.

- Passionately motivated and drove management development program.
- Drove sales to exceed the budget targets.
- Managed store operations, HR, cash office and health and safety.
- Placed orders and managed 600 to 700 cartons delivery on a daily basis.
- Actively monitored cost to ensure wages are in line with cost to sale.
- Drove efficiency and productivity to exceed KPI targets.
- Conducted investigations, disciplinary, grievance and appeal hearings.
- Overall store responsibility for ensuring H&S standards are adhered to.
- Actively supported management recruitment and conducting interviews.

#### **Role:** Manager

September 2014 - April 2017

- Coached and supported the management team in the store and ensured training needs are met to increase efficiency and achieve high standards.
- Ran the store in the absence of Store Manager as the on duty manager.
- Supported weekly payroll using E-time/Core in the absence of HR manager, running the weekly safe check using smart cash.
- Drove and monitored sales in multiple departments ensuring all targets are met.
- Led and managed five managers, including one senior department manager and three department managers, one weekend manager, eight supervisors, and 130 staff.
- Conducted investigation, DHs, and probationary review meetings.
- Responsibility for ensuring H&S standards are adhered to supporting in recruitment, conducting interviews.

#### **Role:** Customer Services Manager

January 2010 - March 2013

- Managed a large team of four trainee managers, two weekend managers, thirty supervisors, and over 250 staff.
- Drove operations of 104 tills including customer service and VAT desk.
- Delivered high levels of customer service.
- Ensured store operations were up to standards at all times.
- Ensured staff levels were adequate at all times to meet customer expectations.
- Responsible for getting over 90,000 customers served in a week on average.
- Handled customer complaints to obtain maximum customer satisfaction.
- Coached and developed managers/supervisors and the store team.

#### **Education**

## Lloyds College, London, England

Post Graduate Diploma in Iformation Technology August 2006

### **Professional Certifications**

Cloud Native Computing Foundation USA, Certified Kubernetes Application Developer

Sun Microsystems USA, Certified Web Component Developer

Sun Microsystems USA, Certified Java Programmer